本字幕由 ShinY 深影字幕组 原创翻译制作
深影字幕组论坛地址 http://shinybbs.com
翻译： 许块块 Cancy Sunny HTC Isis YU 打狗棒
校对： 闲鱼一条 iamazed   后期： iamazed
你是唯一赞同我的人
You're the only one who agrees with me.
可不是嘛 我也超不懂吸血鬼那套的
Yeah. I don't get the vampire thing, either.
他们总是板着个脸
They're all in such bad moods.
是啊 都闷闷不乐的
I know. They're so mopey.
就像是 反正你们死不了
It's like, so you're undead.
高兴点 去晒晒太阳 是不?
Cheer up and get a tan, am I right?
没错
You are right.
- 你不错嘛 - 是么
- That was good. - Yeah?
和我教你的一样
Just like I showed you.
- 那琥珀... - 真有你的 韦弗
- So, Amber... - Well done, Weaver.
谢了
Thank you.
她们什么意思?
What was that for?
没事 你刚说什么?
Nothing. Um, what were you saying?
我最近一直听人谈论即将到来的舞会
I've been hearing quite a bit of talk about an upcoming dance.
然后呢?
Yeah?
然后我想问你
And I was wondering if...
是否愿意...
You would...
哇 琥珀 不错嘛
Wow, Amber, nice score.
十分感谢
Thank you so much.
抱歉 我刚分心了
Sorry. I'm totally distracted.
杰里米邀请我去舞会
Jeremy asked me to the dance.
我知道 难以置信
I know. It's crazy.
每个女生都想被他邀请 结果他邀请了我
Every girl wanted him to ask her, and he asked me.
我有种戴安娜王妃...才会有的那种感觉
I feel like princess Diana... Would have felt
如果查尔斯王子不是近亲结婚的小孩
if prince Charles wasn't the product of inbreeding.
你怎么在这?
Why are you here right now?
最好你是来给奶奶报丧的
Grandma had better be dead.
很遗憾 奶奶活得好好的
Grandma's fine, sadly.
那你在这究竟是个什么情况?
What is it that you could possibly be doing?
我和爸爸是一起来报名做舞会监护人
I'm signing your father and myself up as chaperones for the dance.
那我就报名参军 去阿富汗
Well, then I'm signing up for the army. Afghanistan.
做拆雷的工兵 成吗?
I'm going to be a minesweeper. Deal?
我知道这对你来说很糟
I know this is horrible for you,
但我还是义无反顾
but I'm doing it anyway,
因为你爸和我是在舞会相遇的
because your father and I met at a dance,
所以我想去 我也有权这么做
and I want to, and I deserve to get something I want.
但我允许你对我们约法三章
But I will allow you to give us three guidelines.
别站我旁边 别跟我对视
No standing near me, no looking at me,
别跳舞 就这么多
no dancing, period.
- 那要... - 韦氏独舞也不行
- Even... - That includes the Weaver running man.
很好 成交
All right. Done.
尽管你的父亲会万分失望
Although your father will be disappointed.
要是你破了我的约法三章
If you break any of my rules,
我就和杰里米大尺度亲热
I will make out with Jeremy so hard,
当着你的面
so in front of you,
让你无法直视 甚至闭上眼都会脑补出
you won't be able to close your eyes without picturing
别的小伙手在你闺女的丰臀上缠绵
some guy's hand groping your daughter's butt.
也许你会幻想沙滩
You'll try to think of the beach,
或是开心事助你安眠
or something happy so you can sleep.
但你总是事与愿违
But you won't be able to.
他的十指
His hands.
我的丰臀
My butt.
缠绵整晚
All night.
我想我们都会玩得开心的
I think we'll all have a great time.
是啊 应该不错
Yeah. It should be good.
再见了 亲爱的
Bye, sunshine.
- 噢 - 天啊
- Oh. - Man.
礼服闪亮登场
Now this is a suit.
那腹带湛蓝如你的眼睛
The cummerbund was the same blue as your eyes...
还有我的眼影
And my eye shadow.
你们是说高中舞会
Now you were saying that high school dances
不仅仅只是跳舞喽?
are not just about dancing?
没错 它们更像是爱情作战区
Right. They're kind of like a love war zone.
有伤心的 追求的 拒绝的
There's heartbreak, pursuit, rejection...
太多拒绝了
So much rejection.
我和马蒂的那次舞会就包含了所有元素
And at this dance, Marty and I had the whole shebang.
那是一个充斥眼泪与戏剧化的夜晚
It was a night of drama and tears,
好在最后我们意识到
but in the end, we realized...
- 我们是天作之合 - 多费劲啊
- We were soul mates. - How exhausting.
为什么不直接跳过前戏
Why wouldn't you skip all that first part?
有时要先行之
Well, sometimes you have to get it wrong
才知此路不可行嘛
before you get it right, you know?
事实上是 我们不这样
Actually, we don't.
察布隆人完美把握了
Zabvronians are so perfectly in tune
宇宙真理 绝不会走错路
with the universal truth that we don't get it wrong.
到了两人寻觅伴侣的时候
When it is time for two beings to find each other,
难以抵抗的力量会让我们伸出脚
we are pulled onto our feet by an intractable force
无论他们身在何处
and the same thing is happening to our mate,
我们的伴侣也会做出同样的动作
wherever they may be.
随后我们被这力量牵引到神圣之地
Hmm. And we are pulled by this force to a nearby holy space
也就是你们所谓的爱的田野
which you call a love field.
不 我们没有这说法
Oh, no. We don't call anything a love field.
- 没有吗? - 没有
- No? - No.
随便了 我们就是这样相遇
Well, anyway, that's how we meet,
然后 我们就一起永远幸福快乐地生活着
and from that moment forward, we are together and in harmony for all eternity.
也不总是幸...
Well, not always in har...
- 永远幸福快乐地生活 - 抱歉
- In harmony for all eternity. - Sorry.
我不确定会喜欢那么简单
Well, I wonder if I'd like it being that easy.
约会过程的纠结 "会不会在一起"
The whole drama of dating, the "will-they-won't-they?"
这才是高中舞会的精髓所在
That's what high school dances are all about.
还有超炫的礼服
Well, that and the cool suit.
他还留着他的呢
Oh, he still has his.
你想看吗 拉里? 过来
You wanna see it, Larry? Come on.
我真心只是来给你送报纸的
I honestly just wanted to bring your newspaper
然后就回...噢 每次我都被困住
and go ho... oh. I always get sucked in.
黛比・韦弗
Debbie Weaver,
你能再跟我多说说你和真命天子马蒂如何相遇的吗?
will you tell me more about how you met your soul mate Marty?
让我们调点儿含羞草酒一起翻翻毕业纪念册吧?
Let's make mimosas and find the yearbooks, huh?
她行动快捷 很放松
She's pretty fast and loose
- 借着调含羞草酒的借口... - 嘘 嘘 嘘
- with the excuses for mimosas... - Shh, shh, shh.
噢 这简直太棒了
Oh. This is so great.
我当时的舞伴是格雷格・泰西
Greg tansey was my date.
等一下 马蒂不是你的舞伴?
Wait. Marty wasn't your date?
不是啊 我们和别人约会 事情是这样的
No. We went with other people. That's the story.
- 噢 - 格雷格开车来接我
- Oh. - So Greg picks me up
用那辆从他老爸那借来的酷车
in this really cool car he borrowed from his dad.
超梦幻
Totally dreamy.
- 他戴着华丽丽的腕花来敲门 - 胸衣?
- He comes to the door with the perfect corsage. - Corsage?
corsage也有胸衣之意
噢 那是一种绕在手腕的花
Oh, it's a flower you strap to your wrist.
男孩子邀请女孩子去舞会时用的
It's what boys bring girls for dances.
手腕花环? 听起来真搞
A wrist flower? That sounds preposterous,
- 不过现在还蛮想要一个的 - 是吧?
- and yet now I really want one. - Right?
噢 我很激动 但是...
Oh, I was so excited. But then...
他爽约了 但是马蒂
He stood you up. But Marty,
住在你隔壁 有着更酷发型的马蒂
who lived next door and had much better hair,
带你去了?
took you anyway?
不 我和格雷格去了舞会
No. Greg and I went to the dance.
但是他和他哥们儿去玩了
But he runs off to hang with his guy friends,
把我一个人留在那儿
totally leaving me alone.
我很尴尬
I was so embarrassed.
飙着泪跑了出去
I burst into tears and ran outside.
虽然我知道一定会没事的
I know it's all going to be fine,
但是还是禁不住心头一紧
but I'm still so nervous that it won't be.
我打起精神
So I pulled myself together,
走进去给自己拿了杯饮料
and I go inside to get myself a glass of punch.
而站在饮料台旁边的就是...
And standing by the punch bowl is...
格雷格・泰西的爸爸 他来要回他的车
Greg tansey's father. He wanted his car back.
不 是马蒂
No. Marty.
他和那个垃圾女孩参加舞会
He had gone to the dance with this trashy girl,
丽萨・小脆饼
Lisa Biscotti.
他们也处得不是很愉快
And they were having a horrible time, too.
所以他递了我一杯饮料
So he poured me a glass of punch,
我立刻被逗乐了
had me laughing right away.
我本打算只聊个三五分钟
I thought we spoke for five minutes.
但最后我们聊了一个小时
It ended up being almost an hour.
恋爱时时光飞逝如梭啊
Time flew because you were in love.
没错
Exactly.
所以我们决定和各自的舞伴分开
So we decided to break it off with our dates,
我们走向舞池
we met on the dance floor,
他把我拉入怀中
he pulled me in close,
和着"织梦者"的歌曲共舞
and we danced to "Dream Weaver."
就是你的名字啊
Which is your name.
太完美了 你的名字在这首歌里出现了
It was perfect, because your name is in the song.
你开始上道了
You are getting it now.
这就是我为什么想做这次的舞会监护人的原因
That's why I want to chaperone this dance, you know?
有的时候 能有件事儿提醒我们
Sometimes it's nice to have a reminder
一切是如何开始的也挺好
of where it all started.
我觉得高中舞会
I think a high school dance
就是世界上最激动人心和浪漫的地方
sounds like the most exciting, romantic place in the world.
让我们一起看约翰・休斯的舞会电影
Let's watch John Hughes movies about dances
上世纪九十年代好莱坞知名青春片导演
再喝些含羞草酒吧
and make more mimosas.
事实上不过是橘子汁
They're mostly orange juice.
我觉得她没有喝多 真的
I think she has it under control. I really do.
夫君 我想要个"会不会在一起"
Husband, I want a "will-they-won't-they."
好的 在亚马逊下个单
Fine. Order one on Amazon.
- 你可以用我的信用卡 - 不
- You can put it on the credit card. - No.
我想要个你赢得我芳心的梦幻故事
I want a dramatic story about how you won me.
我们在一起的过程太随便了
The way we got together was so easy.
太无聊了
So boring.
噢 没错 宇宙让我们走到了一起
Oh, yes. The universe drew us together
超越时间和空间成就的完美结合
through space and time to a perfect union.
多么无聊的事儿啊
What a snooze festival.
我想要的是曲折的故事 不舍的追求
I want drama, pursuit.
我要你追求我
I want you to chase me.
- 怎么? 追去厨房? - 只是打个比方
- What, into the kitchen? - Metaphorically.
你想让我打个比方追你到厨房?
You want me to metaphorically chase you into the kitchen?
我希望经历百转千回之后 你才赢得我的芳心
I want you to win me after a twisty, turny story
虽然看起来你不会
where it seems like you won't,
带着满满的失望和腕上的花
filled with disappointment and wrist flowers,
之后 当我以为就这样的时候
and then, just when all is lost,
一辆梦幻的轿车
a dreamy car.
但是我已经赢得你了
But I already won you.
- 是吗? - 我没有吗?
- Have you? - Have I?
噢 不是这样的
Oh, that's not how you do it.
我现在会马上冲出去
I'm going to storm out dramatically.
噢 亲爱的 别开玩笑了!
Oh, darling, don't be ridiculous!
你要带我去舞会!
You're taking me to that dance!
噢...拜托 小南瓜!
Oh... come on, pumpkin!
啊 估计这就是我这周的活儿了
Ugh. I guess this is what I'm doing this week.
你好 我是雷吉
Hello. I'm Reggie.
我注意到你好像朋友不是很多
I noticed you don't have any friends
很可能在为舞伴而烦恼
and might be desperate for a date.
是的 我是吉塞尔...
That's true. I'm Giselle...
- 和那个模特名字一样 - 棒极了
- Like the model. - Great.
吉赛尔・邦辰: 巴西性感超模
我最近才学到了找到灵魂伴侣的方法
So I recently learned that the way you find your soul mate
便是和错的人一起去参加舞会
is to go to the dance with the wrong person,
当你在饮料台帮找到灵魂伴侣之后就和她分手
who you then break up with after you find your soul mate at the punch bowl.
所以我在想
So I was wondering,
你愿不愿意当我那个错的人
would you like to be my wrong person,
我要甩的那个人?
the one I will dump?
我们能去我父母的房子照个像么?
Can we still take pictures at my parents' house?
可以
Sure.
好的 太棒了
Okay. Awesome.
你可以去看看我的乌龟
You can meet my turtle.
听起来有点怪 不过我八点来接你
That's weird, but I'll pick you up at 8:00.
好的
Okay.
你的舞伴来了
Your date has arrived.
亲爱的 你太美了
Oh, honey, you look beautiful.
我还配了水钻
I even pulled out the rhinestones.
到晚上 我将会光彩照人
My neck will be green by 10:00.
噢 对了...
Oh, oh. And...
我给你准备了胸花
I got you a boutonniere.
你还给我准备了这个啊
You got me flowers?
我没想到我们需要这大费周章
I didn't realize we were going all out.
我要去换套正装么? 我可以...
You want me to wear the suit? I could...
不用 你已经很帅了
No, you look handsome.
很好 我也不想整晚都收着腹
Good, 'cause I don't think I can hold my stomach in all night.
抱一个
Come here.
好吧 这种搂搂抱抱的事
Okay. This whole touching each other thing,
今晚别再做了
this is the last of that.
- 哇 - 噢 她美得像个天使
- Wow. - Oh, she's an angel.
我们今晚的谈话也就到此为止了
And thus ends our talking for the night.
杰里米到了吗?
Is Jeremy outside?
让他进来坐坐吧 我们想跟他聊聊
Bring him in here. We wanna meet him.
- 对了 我们照张相吧 - 马上
- Oh, I need pictures. - Right.
那你们还不如借个哈勃太空望远镜
Well, then you'd better borrow someone's hubble telescope,
这样你才能看清楚我们的一举一动
because that's as close as you're going to get to us.
- 就一张 - 不行
- Just one. - No.
- 就一张你和我的? - 没门
- Just one of me and you? - Not happening.
- 马蒂 马蒂 快拍照 - 马上 马上
- Marty, Marty, take a picture. - Almost. Almost.
- 好的 - 快快快
- Okay. - Now. Now. Now.
快
Now.
没拍到 只有门
Nope. All door.
噢 希望她玩得开心
Oh, I hope she has fun.
我希望今晚是个梦幻之夜
I hope it's magical.
我倒希望只是柏拉图式的
Well, I hope it's platonic.
也希望杰里米被阉了
And I hope that Jeremy's a eunuch.
到时是我们去接他们 还是他们自己回来?
Are we picking them up, or are they gonna meet us here?
什么? 谁? 你在说什么?
What? Who them? What are you talking about?
你们几个 不要激动
Guys? Hey. Hey. Hey. Hey.
- 有话好好说 - 不许动粗!
- Break it up. - No roughhousing!
哪凉快哪呆着去!
Take it to the shower where it belongs!
走吧 走吧
Go. Go.
如果他们只是想自己出来玩玩
If the boys just wanted to hang out with each other,
那还带上我们干嘛?
why did they even bring us?
我也不知道
I have no idea.
这里太好玩了
Well, I'm so glad I came.
但是拉里 杰西看起来有点不开心
You know what, though, Larry? Jackie seems a little upset.
我认为你该过去和她聊聊
You should go talk to her, I think.
噢 不用 别担心 我懂我妻
Oh, no. Don't worry. I know my wife.
你知道我们该干什么吗?
You know what we should do?
我们该到孩子们抽烟的地方去
Let's go outside where the kids smoke
然后唬得他们像蟑螂一样四处窜
and watch 'em scatter like cockroaches.
噢 马蒂・韦弗 你真有趣
Oh, Marty Weaver, you are fun.
- 你也有趣 - 哥们 别逼我动手
- You're fun! - Don't you start with me, big boy.
- 那你想和我打? - 你想试试 是吧 哥们?
- Oh, you wanna start with me? - Oh, you wanna start something, do you, big boy?
是的 我就是想和你试试 我现在就要和你试试
Yeah, I wanna start with you. I'm gonna start with you.
有时候想吸引他们还真难
Sometimes it's hard to stay attracted to them.
太难了
So hard.
太有趣了...星期一和星期三
It's interesting... mondays and wednesdays,
我做上肢运动 星期二和星期四
I do upper bod, Tuesdays and Thursdays,
我做下肢运动 星期五是有氧运动
I do lower. Fridays are cardio.
今天坐下蹲的时候 我突然想到...
But today, I was doing squats, when I realized...
今天是星期五啊
It's Friday.
然后怎样呢?
So what'd you do?
改成有氧运动呗
Switched to cardio.
真不敢相信他是你的舞伴
I can't believe that he's your date.
她是他的舞伴
She's his date.
能留下你号码么
I should get your number.
我现在就想给你发短信
I'm gonna start texting you now.
天哪
Oh, my.
这里布置得好迷人 是吗?
It really is quite magical, isn't it?
这儿真美
It's nice.
有时我会点起几根蜡烛 坐到衣橱里
Sometimes I light candles and sit in my closet.
这样也不错哦
It's nice, too.
好吧
Okay.
我要去饮料台旁等我的真爱了
I'm going to the punch bowl to wait for my soul mate.
我可以站在你身边吗?
Can I stand near you?
还是你希望我保持距离?
Or would you like me to keep my distance?
吉塞尔...
Giselle...
还是保持距离吧
Keep your distance.
天哪 今晚太棒了
Oh, my God. That was awesome.
姑娘们 你们错过精彩部分了
Girls, you missed it.
我们去追那几个拿着酒瓶的孩子
We chased down these kids with a flask.
他们还想跳过灌木丛逃走
They tried to get away by jumping over these bushes,
但摔了个狗吃屎
but they fell in face-first.
还血迹斑斑的
There was blood.
当舞会监护人的感觉真棒
I love chaperoning.
一部讲述青少年恋爱的喜剧电影
夫君! 我想要《美丽粉色》里的情节
Husband! I want to be "pretty in pinked,"
现在就要
and I want it now.
可你彻底搞砸了
You're completely dropping the ball.
你这么说可不对 我觉得我表现得挺好的
Oh, I disagree. I think I'm doing great.
你连腕花都没给我准备一个
You didn't even give me a wrist flower.
我为什么要为你弄死自己的花?
Why would I kill one of my flowers for you?
因为你想得到我
Because you are trying to get me.
我们都是老夫老妻了
But I already have you.
拉里 你应该追过去
Larry, you should go after her.
如我所言 我懂我妻 现在还不是时候
Like I said, I know my wife. Now is not the time.
快 有人在舞池内有不当举动!
Oh! Below-the-waist touching on the dance floor!
我马上过来
I'll be with you in a sec.
太疯狂了 他今晚挺高兴的
Crazy. He's having fun.
那你能陪你的舞伴一会儿吗 哪怕一分钟?
So, think you could hang with your date for, like, a minute?
等一下 你是真的生气了吗?
Wait, are you... you really mad at me?
我以为只是出来做监护 原来你是当约会啊?
I thought we were chaperoning. Is this a date?
好吧 是的
Well, yeah.
我想重温我们坠入爱河的那晚
I wanted to relive the night we fell in love.
那我去看看D.J.有没有那首"织梦者"
How about I go see if the D.J. has "Dream Weaver,"
然后你和你家老头跳一支啊
and then you give your old man a dance,
我还记得一些时髦的动作哦
because I still have some funky moves.
- 噢 真的? - 真的 想看吗?
- Oh, you do? - Yeah, you wanna see?
- 跳跳咯 - 想看?
- Let's see. - Wanna see it?
- 记得这个不? - 噢 我喜欢的
- Remember this one? - Oh. I like it.
当我用手这样动的时候 你喜欢吗?
You like this, when I do this with the arms?
这个姿势?
The attitude?
天啊 完了 停 停下
Oh, my God. Stop. Stop.
- 去拿点喝的给我 -好吧
- Go get me some punch. - All right.
好吧 马上回来
All right, be right back.
嗨 雷吉 你在干嘛呢?
Hey, Reggie, what are you doing?
黛比・韦弗告诉过我
Debbie Weaver told me
如何在饮料台旁与他们的灵魂伴侣邂逅
about how humans meet their soul mates by the punch bowl.
然后我就在这里了
So I'm here.
不 兄弟 这只是我和黛比的邂逅过程
No, buddy, that's just how Debbie and I got together.
不是每个人的邂逅过程
That's not everybody's story.
所以我很迷茫
So I am so confused.
那我和我的灵魂伴侣邂逅的故事是什么?
What's my soul mate story?
哥们 不要让女人控制你的理智吗?
Buddy, don't let the ladies get into your head, okay?
邂逅故事只是...故事
Stories are just that... stories.
我跟你说个秘密好吗?
Can I tell you a secret?
就是我们邂逅的那个舞蹈?
That dance that we met at?
当我和我的舞伴黄了的时候
When I went outside to break it off with my date,
她哭得很伤心 我很努力地安慰她
she was very upset, so I tried to comfort her.
然后 你懂的 一来二去 然后...
And then, you know, one thing led to another, and...
- 懂我意思么? - 还有别的意思吗
- You get what I'm saying? - Not if there's subtext.
我们在图书馆亲热 就在一堆书后面
We made out in the library, up against a bunch of books.
我都没有正式和她分手
I didn't even officially break up with her.
当我回去时 黛比在那
You know, so then when I got back, Debbie was there,
然后你懂的 "织梦者"
and, you know, "Dream Weaver,"
然后巴拉巴拉巴拉
and blah, blah, blah, blah, blah.
所以你看 没人能真正知道
So you see, no one ever really knows
他们是怎么找到他们的灵魂伴侣的
how they found their soul mate.
或者他们的婚姻是建立在谎言之上的!
Or if their marriage was based on lies!
不 不是的 宝贝 我不是说...
No, no, honey, I wasn't saying...
"巴拉巴拉巴拉"?
"Blah, blah, blah, blah, blah"?
呸! 禽兽!
Ugh! Animal!
你没看到她站在那吗?
You didn't see her standing there?
就是我们聊天...你没看见她?
Like, while we were talk... never saw her?
高中舞会烂毙了
High school dances suck.
男孩蠢毙了
Guys suck.
为什么他们要那样做?
Why don't they stop doing that?
- 我哪知道 - 我们都不会那样做
- I don't know. - We don't do that.
不那么过分 不会
Not as much, no.
给你纸 亲爱的
Here you go, sweetheart.
这是最伤心的部分
That's the worst part.
唉 上帝
Oh, God.
嗨 你为什么不和你的舞伴还有她的乌龟...
Hey. Why aren't you dancing with your date...
跳舞呢?
And her turtle?
我不怎么想去
I don't really feel like it.
你今晚怎么了?
So what's up with you tonight?
一直在饮料台旁边溜达
You've been lurking by the punch bowl,
现在还生闷气
and now you're sulking.
看起来像个郁郁寡欢的吸血鬼 哈?
Acting a little moody vampire-y, huh?
只是有点小伤心因为...
Just a little sad because...
我以为当我跟你说了之后今晚会是...
I thought tonight would be the night when...
我认为的那个夜晚
When I told you something.
雷吉 我一直在等着
Reggie, I've been waiting for this.
- 真的? - 是啊
- You have? - Yeah.
好吧 我是说 我不知道外星人也有这样的倾向
Well, I mean, I didn't know that aliens could swing that way,
但同性恋也挺好的
but it's so cool to be gay.
外星人基友
Alien gay.
简直酷毕了 哥们
Totally rock 'n' roll, man.
不 琥珀 不是的 我不是同性恋
No. Amber, no. I am not the gay.
我以为今晚会是你意识到
I thought tonight would be the night that you realized
你和杰里米那个运动员不合适...
that you'd gotten it wrong with Jeremy the jock...
我才是你的灵魂伴侣
And that I'm your soul mate.
雷吉 我觉得你很棒
Reggie, I think you're great,
但直到今晚 你仍然只是我的朋友
but until tonight, you were my only friend.
你可能是我唯一真正的朋友
And you're probably still my only real friend.
我不知道我会不会把你当做其他的朋友
I just don't know if I really see you that other way.
对不起
I'm sorry.
这简直就是我最悲伤的感觉了
This is the worst thing I've ever felt!
我的胃在烧! 我的心在痛!
My stomach is burning! My heart's aching!
我觉得我要死了!
I think I'm gonna die!
噢! 儿子!
Oh! My son!
我要做什么? 他要死了吗？
What do I do? Is he dying?
我要怎么修补他? 这管用吗?
How do I fix it? Does this help?
她还以为我是基佬
She thought I was gay.
- 呃... - 好吧 打扰下 同志们
- Well... - Okay, I'm sorry, guys,
但你们做再多也不能摆脱这个感觉
but there's not much you can do to make this go away.
但好消息是你不会死
But the good news is you're not dying.
它就是那么痛那么悲
It just feels like it.
人类怎么能承受它?
How can humans stand this?
好吧 我们通常以我们的方式排解它
Well, often, we eat our way through it.
悲伤情歌可以缓解
Sad songs help.
或者跟鼓手亲热
And making out with drummers.
但其实你需要的只是时间
But mostly, you just need time.
这才是最重要的
That's the big one.
我要承受这种痛苦很久?
I gotta feel like this for a long time?
没错 可能还不止一次
Yeah. And probably more than once.
什么?!
What?!
你可能会以为你已经找到灵魂伴侣了
You may think that you totally found your soul mate.
但她可能不那么认为
And she doesn't feel the same way,
但那说明你们不是灵魂伴侣
but that just means you weren't soul mates.
- 啊! - 回到舞会
- Aah! - So get back out there,
继续寻找 因为你一定会找到的
and keep looking, 'cause you will find her.
没错 就像黛比・韦弗会找到她真正的灵魂伴侣一样
Yes. Like Debbie Weaver will find her real soul mate.
今晚她很痛苦是因为她知道了
Tonight she suffers because she has learned
她的真命天子并非马蒂 但她会重整旗鼓
it isn't Marty, but she will get back out there,
找到真正的那个他 尽管她年纪偏大了
and she will find him, despite her age.
不 不 不是这么回事
No. No. That's not it at all.
虽说马蒂那时候是个叛逆的
I mean, Marty may have been a completely revolting
十六岁不良少年
little monster of a 16-year-old,
但那晚他让我笑 而不是哭
but he made me laugh that night instead of cry.
很多很多次 多到数不清了
And there have been a million times since
他总能让我破涕为笑
where he has turned my tears into laughter,
通常是靠跳韦氏独舞
often via the Weaver running man...
他都不知道那舞很有趣
Which he doesn't even know is funny.
他自己都不知道诶
He doesn't even know it.
他就是我的真命天子
He is my soul mate.
这就是宇宙真理
And that is the universal truth.
亲 别给他发短信了 往前看呐
Honey, stop texting him and move on.
会找到你的那个他的 相信我
There are drummers in your future. Trust me.
她懂的可真多
Wow. She knows a lot.
可不是么
Yes, she does.
我打算回舞池去了
I think I'm gonna go back to the dance.
去吧 仔儿
Go, my son.
我以你为荣
I'm so proud of you.
而我呢 要回家了
And I am going home.
因为我的真命天子
Because my soul mate,
那个我注定要
and the man who I am destined
共度一生的男人
to spend all of eternity with,
就是个蠢货
is a jackass.
图书馆 是吧?
The library, huh?
重温旧梦?
Reliving old memories?
所有理想的生闷气地方都被
Well, all the good sulking spots were taken
痴男怨女 金童玉女 潘亢谀径占据了
by crying, kissing, or puking teenagers, so...
黛比...
Deb...
我很抱歉
I'm so sorry.
那是必须的
Well, you should be.
因为这次这梁子结定了
Because this... this is officially a thing.
你是个骗子
You were a weasel,
这辈子我都会这么念叨你
and you will hear about it for the rest of time.
那你笑什么?
So why are you smiling?
因为呢 虽然丽萨・小脆饼夺走了我的故事
Because Lisa Biscotti may have taken my story,
但今晚 我们要夺回图书馆
but tonight, we are takin' back the library.
这真是个生闷气的好地方
This was a good place to sulk.
嗨 吉塞尔
Hi, Giselle.
今晚我发现了一件有趣的事
I've learned something really interesting tonight...
我的乌龟喜欢饶舌
my turtle likes rap.
我对我之前的行为道歉
Sorry about how I've been acting.
没关系 我本来就有点奇怪
It's okay. I'm a little weird.
那没事 因为我更奇怪
It's okay. I bet I'm weirder.
那倒没有吧
That's unlikely.
我真的更奇怪
I'm weirder.
和我最亲近的生物就是这只绿东西了
My closest relationship is with a green creature
而它大半辈子都躲在自己的壳里
who spends most of its life hiding in its shell.
我完全理解
I can relate.
那...不如我去拿两杯饮料?
So... why don't I go grab us a couple of glasses of punch?
三杯吧
Make it three?
夫君
Husband.
戏剧性!
Drama!
大圆满结局!
Happy ending!
都有了
They will.
你是来虏获我的芳心的吗?
Are you winning me?
希望如此
I hope I am.
但也许太迟了
But maybe I'm too late.
不 不 你来的刚刚好
No. No. You are just in time.
我本来以为完全没戏
I was sure that all was lost.
我得让你这么觉得
Well, I had to make you feel that way
才能达到现在这么好的效果
for this to be so good, right?
你藏的够深啊
It was a long con.
这是谁的车?
Whose car is this?
谁知道 某富二代吧
I have no idea. Some brat.
开心不?
You happy?
这就是我想要的
It's exactly what I wanted.
正如我常说的那样...
Like I keep saying...
我懂我妻
I know my wife.
那些兔崽子又在抽烟了
Those little bastards are smoking again.
嘿 说你呢!
Hey! You!
嗨 抱歉
Hi. Sorry.
不 我才该说抱歉
No. I'm sorry.
你还好吗?
Are you all right?
我对我之前说的话道歉
I'm sorry about what I said before.
我希望这不会让我们之间产生隔阂
I hope it doesn't make things weird.
不 我很抱歉
No. I'm sorry.
没事了
We're cool.
别放在心上
It's all cool.
很好
Great.
往好了看
On the bright side,
我发现乌龟女孩其实还挺有趣的
turns out turtle girl is actually quite interesting.
谁知道呢 也许我的位置在舞池边
Who knows? Maybe my spot was next to the dance floor,
而不是饮料台旁
not the punch bowl.
大爱这首歌
I love this song!
我最爱的剧《真爱如血》里头有这歌
They used it in "true blood," my favorite show.
有人觉得我长得像里面的那个吸血鬼
Some people think that I look like the main vampire guy.
你觉得呢? 我在商场里碰见过他一次
Do you think so? I met him in a mall once.
我们的下巴一模一样 而且都斜视
We have the same jaw and we both squint.
也有人觉得我像是马特・达蒙
Other people think that I look like if Matt Damon
前三部《谍影重重》主演
和伊森・霍克的混合体
and Ethan Hawke had a baby together.
《爱在黎明破晓前》系列的男主
我也不知道真的假的
I don't know about that, though.
我舅妈琼觉得我像米拉・乔沃维奇
My auntie June thinks that I look like Milla Jovovich.
《生化危机》女主
这是闹哪样? 她可是个女的
What's that supposed to mean? She's a girl.
美国老一代电影人
我外公说我像华伦・比提
My grandpa said that I look like Warren Beatty.
我也不知道...
I have no idea...
散开
Break it up.
嘿 嘿 嘿 嘿!
Hey, hey, hey, hey!
又看到你们了!
That's the second time!
不是吧?
Seriously?
哦 该死
Oh, shoot.
真可悲
That's sad.
不要管奶罩了!
Leave the bra!
知道了! 走! 走!
Oh! Okay! Go! Go!
不要再让我看到你两出现在这!
I don't want to see the two of you in here ever again!
明白否?
Is that clear?
非常明白!
Crystal!
我听到你们了
I can hear you.